BLOOD AND BLACK LACE
Directed by MARIO BAVA
What 's got into you ? Why did you come here ?
Don 't you realise that Isabella could see us ?
- Have you got any ? - No .
I can 't take this any more .
If I don 't get some soon I 'll go crazy .
Don 't be like that , Franco . Have you tried asking Isabella ?
We had an argument .
She even stole what I had , damn her .
Try to hang on in there .
When I 've finished work we 'll find some .
Trust me . I 'll help you .
Now go .
I 'm counting on you . Thanks . I 'll be waiting .
Bye .
Isabella . Your scarf .
Thank you .
- Bye . - Bye .
What 's wrong ?
The sign 's fallen off again .
- Do you want me to go and fix it ? - No , not tonight .
You can do it in the morning .
Same old story ... Isabella 's late again .
I don 't know what 's wrong with that girl . This is the third time .
There 's no need to get angry , just give her a hefty fine .
I certainly will , and I 'll fire her if she 's as late as she was yesterday .
- Good night , Madame . - Good night .
Nicole .
Look at this dress . Try to take more care of the clothes .
There 's another show tomorrow . Look at this .
- I 'll be more careful . Sorry . - You 're always rushing off out of here .
You 're all the same , that 's all you think about .
What does she expect ? She 's so annoying .
It 's not easy being a widow .
Isabella !
No , thanks .
- How long were the lights off ? - Ten minutes .
How long had the girl worked for you ?
About two years .
What was she like ?
Very lively .
A bit unruly , but there 's nothing bad I could say about her .
As far as you know , did she have a lot of friends ?
Inspector , I 'm not going to be much help here .
I 'm the managing director .
You should ask the two girls who lived with her .
I can 't believe it . Such a terrible thing . I still can 't get my head round it .
Poor thing , she was always so cheerful , so ...
Come on , stop crying . It 's not going to do any good .
Inspector Silverstri , this is Countess Cristiana , the owner of the company .
- Good morning . - Good morning .
Haven 't I met you before , madam ? Or am I mistaken ?
Yes , we have actually met before .
Because of my husband 's accident .
Exactly . It was a car accident .
I imagine you 'll be able to help me . You must know all about your girls .
Inspector , this isn 't a boarding school .
I don 't know or care about what they do when they 're not here .
All right , I 'm going to be in the studio .
- Will you excuse me ? - Of course .
Come on , Peggy . Stop crying .
What good is it going to do ?
Come on .
What time was it when you went out to fix the sign ?
About seven . It was banging and the noise was irritating Madame Cristiana .
I went out and fixed it as best I could .
I protest !
Mr Morlachi , I demand an explanation .
I 'd only just come through the gates when these men grabbed me .
- Ask the inspector . - Inspector ?
Calm down and tell me why you 're here .
- I 'm Marquis Riccardo Morelli ... - All right , but answer my question .
He 's come to pick me up . He 's my fiancé .
Fiancé !
- Why are you laughing ? - Because we live together .
Did you know Isabella ?
Isabella ?
You introduced us once , didn 't you ?
Yes , I guess I knew her , but only by sight .
I see .
Come on , Peggy .
Be strong .
Stop crying .
It looks like she 's the only one who 's upset .
They were very good friends .
- Did she live with you two ? - Yes .
Who had she gone out with ? Who was the last person to see her ?
I don 't know .
Leave her alone . Everybody knows who Isabella 's lover was .
- Who are you ? - Cesare Lazzarini , fashion designer .
- Will you tell me his name ? - Whose ?
The lover 's .
Scalo . Franco Scalo , the famous antique dealer .
- Police . Where 's the inspector ? - In there .
I can assure you I don 't know anything .
- Excuse me a second . - Sure .
It 's confirmed .
Shall I go ?
- Yes , go . - All right .
So ...
Tell me , what kind of relationship did you have with Isabella ?
- We were friends . - Or lovers ?
I 'm going to admit to something , but you mustn 't be shocked .
I don 't believe in permanent and everlasting relationships .
I understand .
Do you know what this is ?
No , I don 't .
- What is it ? - Cocaine .
It was found in your friend Isabella 's house .
In Isabella 's house ?
- So you didn 't know about this ? - No .
Never mind .
But I must ask you to remain at my disposal .
I 'll see you again .
Autumn Evening .
Turn around .
All right , you can go . Quickly .
- What 's wrong , Cesaretto ? - Isabella was supposed to model this .
- You 're right . - Who should I give it to ?
Let 's see ...
- Peggy ... - Not me , please . I can 't .
For heaven 's sake don 't cry or you 'll ruin your make-up .
- Greta , you model it . - No , I 'm sorry , I can 't wear it .
- Don 't be silly . - It 'll bring me bad luck .
- Someone 's going to have to model it . - I will .
Good . Come on , hurry up .
Why doesn 't that surprise me ? She 's so cynical .
All right , you can go .
Turn round . Good . Walk .
Hold on a second .
Something 's missing .
The brooch ! The green brooch .
We can fix that now . Where is it ?
Isabella brought her own . She kept it in one of these boxes .
Here it is .
Look what I 've found . Isabella kept a diary .
It 'll be an interesting read .
Listen . " He 's a man who arouses deep and desperate feelings in me .
" I 'd be prepared to die for him . "
Let me see .
- I don 't think we 've got the right ... - What are you doing ? Are you all mad ?
Does this seem like the right time ? Go on , off you go . Get ready .
I think we should give this to the police .
I found it and I 'd like to hand it in myself , if you don 't mind .
As you wish .
Ray of Moonlight .
- Hello ? - Hello . Hello , Franco .
Why didn 't you come ?
I was on my way out but I 'm not feeling well . You know why .
Sure , I understand .
Try to come right away . I 've got some .
Listen , Franco . I 've found a diary .
- Isabella 's diary . - What ?
Isabella 's diary ? Who else knows about it ?
Everybody , unfortunately .
I realised too late that there could be something compromising about you in it .
I kept it and said I 'd hand it in to the police .
Good . We 'll have time to take a look at it .
- I 'll come straight over . - You don 't sound well at all , Franco .
Franco !
Franco , can you hear me ?
Yes , Nicole .
Sorry , I can 't even breathe . But now you 've got some I 'll feel better . Bye .
I 'll see you soon .
Hurry up , girls . Greta , you 're on next .
- Everything all right there , Marco ? - Yes , Madame .
- Cesaretto , where were you ? - I 'm here .
I looked everywhere for you . Why do I have to do everything myself ?
- Nicole ? - What is it ?
Telephone call .
- For me ? - Yes , for you .
- Hello ? - Hello . Nicole , is that you ?
- Yes . Who 's speaking ? - It 's Franco .
I can 't make it over there . I feel too ill .
You come over . Please . Now . I feel like I 'm suffocating .
How am I supposed to get away ?
All right , I 'll do my best .
I 'll try to come right away .
There , it 's all right now .
Peggy , Franco 's sick . He needs me .
I need to rush over and see him . Will you lend me your car ?
But the show 's not over yet .
I don 't care . Give me the keys but don 't let anyone see you .
Hold on .
- Peggy , what are you doing ? - Nothing , just getting my handkerchief .
The alarm switch is hidden in the glove compartment .
All right .
Thank you .
ANTIQUES
Franco ?
- Have fun but don 't come home too late . - Don 't worry .
Marco !
I want to keep you company till Tao-Li gets back .
Aren 't you scared of being at home on your own ?
I 'm actually very tired and I 'd like to go straight to bed .
But you 'll have to stay up till Nicole brings your car back .
Please .
All right . As you wish . Come in .
Thank you . I didn 't want to leave you .
I 'd have worried about you being alone in that house .
- Clarice , are you still here ? - Good evening , miss .
Yes , I 've only just finished .
Didn 't Miss Tao-Li come back with you ?
She 's gone to a party . She 'll be home later .
Clarice looks after us .
I 'll be off , then . I left your dinner in the oven to keep it warm .
If Miss Tao-Li wants her concoction , it 's ready . She just needs to heat it up .
Thank you , Clarice . Good night . I 'll see you tomorrow .
Good night .
Peggy ...
- You always refuse to listen to me . - I listen to you .
You don 't . And I 'm tired of telling you the same thing over and over .
I 've told you a thousand times .
Sadly I 've fallen in love with you .
But you don 't care . Why not ?
Calm down and come here .
You see ...
I 'm not well .
I know you think I 'm besotted , and that drives me insane .
I 'm sick , unhappy ...
Don 't be like that . I understand you . I 'm your friend . Come on , cheer up .
- I 'll have one of your cigarettes . - No ! Stop ! Leave it .
What is it ? I just wanted a cigarette . What have I done ?
I 'll get it for you . You 'll mess up my bag otherwise .
Here .
Hello ?
Good evening , it 's Inspector Silverstri .
I 'm sorry to bother you . I 'm calling about your car .
We found it unlocked and abandoned . Had it been stolen ?
No , I lent it to my friend Nicole .
Yes .
Yes , she asked to borrow it so she could visit a friend who wasn 't well .
Has something happened ?
I 'd rather speak to you about this in person .
I 'll come over to your house .
All right , I 'll be here .
What 's going on ?
They 've found my car but not Nicole . Oh , God , what 's happened to her ?
- Is the inspector coming ? - Yes , he wants to speak to me .
I 'll be off , then . I 'd rather the police didn 't find me with you .
Yes , it 's best if nobody knows you came here .
Yes , it is best . Especially for you .
- I 'm sorry . - I 'll see you tomorrow .
See you tomorrow .
" I caught Peggy trying to steal 100,000 lire from my bag .
" She started crying and told me she needed it .
" She 's pregnant but can 't deal with the scandal .
" I lent her the money because I felt sorry for her .
" Tomorrow I 'll ask the bastard for 200,000 lire . "
WHERE IS THE DIARY ?
I burnt it ... I burnt it ...
I burnt it !
Miss Peggy ?
Good evening .
Sorry , I know it 's late for visiting , but this is an urgent matter .
Don 't worry . Please , have a seat .
What 's it about ?
Charles , you can go .
I got back a short while ago and found Nicole in my shop ...
murdered .
My God !
I 'd gone to the studio to pick Nicole up .
Remember ? We bumped into each other .
I looked everywhere but I couldn 't find her .
So I went back home .
Believe me , I 'll never forget what I saw .
Sorry , but why did you come here instead of going to the police ?
Nicole was my friend .
She was killed in my shop .
The police are bound to blame me .
I need an alibi .
- You 've got to help me . - Me ? What have I got to do with this ?
You 're in as much trouble as I am .
We need to say that we were together at the studio until we left .
I 'll vouch for you and you 'll vouch for me .
- It 's in both of our interests . - You 're insane .
The police have no reason to suspect me .
You 're the one who 's in a fix . Maybe you really did kill her .
No . Call the police right now or I 'll do it .
Go on , then , and you can tell them about the lOUs .
What lOUs ?
The IOUs you signed to guarantee a seven million lire loan for Isabella
that you couldn 't pay .
Is that true ? Riccardo , you didn 't tell me . Is it true ?
Oh , my God .
My dear Marquis , you haven 't got a penny to your name .
You 're completely ruined and afraid of the scandal .
That 's a pretty good reason to kill Isabella
and maybe Nicole too , to make sure the police didn 't get hold of the diary .
Who knows , maybe all the expiry dates were written in it .
What diary ? I don 't know anything about it .
Don 't lie , Riccardo . I told you Nicole had found Isabella 's diary .
As you can see , we 're tied to each other by a strong thread .
If you don 't want the police sticking their noses into your business ,
you 'd better do as I say .
I 'll go back to my shop now and call the inspector .
I 'll tell him that we were together all the time . All right ?
Good night .
Why won 't you believe me ? I burnt that diary .
It contained things about me that I didn 't want people to know .
I burnt it . I swear I burnt it .
Believe me . Believe me !
No !
How did that girl get in here ?
- She had a key . - How come ?
I 'd given it to her .
- She used to visit me sometimes . - Her as well ?
You mustn 't think that I ...
I 'd left Isabella for Nicole .
How many other people had keys to that door ?
Nobody else .
- Except me , of course . - Of course .
Did you take drugs with her too ?
- What are you saying , Inspector ? - Come on , Scalo !
Who are you trying to kid ?
You 've got a drug habit . It 's written all over your face .
I can even tell you where you get your drugs .
And ...
as for the girls who , shall we say , keep you company ,
or who try to fight your habit , like Isabella did ,
or who take drugs themselves , like this one ...
That may well be the case ,
but it doesn 't mean that I 'm a murderer .
Besides , I have an alibi . I was with ...
I haven 't asked you about that ... yet .
We 'll talk about it in good time .
- When ? - Right now , in my office .
- Do you recognise it ? - Yes , that 's the one .
- Are you sure ? - Yes .
Hold on . I wrote down the first few numbers .
Here we go ... 4 , 5 , 3 . What did I tell you ?
Did you see if a man or a woman was driving ?
A man , definitely .
He was all in black and he didn 't seem to have a face .
Maybe he was wearing a mask .
Maybe , I don 't know . I looked at him because I heard a horn .
- What horn ? - The car horn , Inspector .
It beeped , but not for very long .
Then suddenly it stopped .
Could there be an alarm connected to the horn , Zanchin ?
Hold on , I 'll check .
Yes , there is one . It 's at the back of the glove compartment .
- How long did it beep for ? - I don 't know .
- Not very long , like I said . - Tell me how long .
That 's it . Pretty much that long .
If you didn 't know where it was , you 'd take a while to find it .
Right .
But if you did know where it was hidden ,
you 'd only need a few seconds .
Come through .
After you .
Have a good look at these men .
Did you ever see any of them in Miss Peggy 's car ?
- Hello , Mr Morlachi . - Hello , Clarice .
You know him ? You 've seen him in the car ?
Of course she 's seen me .
In the car and walking , lots of times . All perfectly normal .
I didn 't say it wasn 't .
Let 's keep going .
- Him . I saw him in the car . - Of course . Big deal .
What 's the point of this ? It 's all a farce .
Be quiet .
You didn 't just see me , did you ?
Open your eyes , you idiot .
Him , for instance . You saw him too , didn 't you ?
Do you only want to know who went in the car with Miss Peggy ?
Why ?
Because that gentleman came to the house last night .
He came with Miss Peggy .
At last we 're getting somewhere .
You bastard ! What are you trying to insinuate ? Do you want to ruin me ?
That 's enough .
Bloody murderer !
Damn you ! Own up to it . You 're the murderer .
Inspector , have him examined . He 's impotent .
That 's why he hates women . He 'd kill them all because he can 't have them .
Why don 't you tell the inspector that that 's why your wife left you ?
Oh , my God . Oh , my God , I 'm suffocating .
- Hold his shoulders . - Calm down .
Take him to the infirmary .
No ! Let me go !
Let me go !
- None of you knew he had epilepsy ? - I didn 't know .
You can go .
Goodbye , Clarice .
I 'm very sorry but I 'm going to have to keep you here , Mr Morlachi ,
and you too , Mr Lazzarini .
- What does " keep you here " mean ? - It means I 'm legally detaining you .
Excuse me , Inspector , but you need a good reason to do that .
Nicole 's murderer had been in Peggy 's car before
because he knew where the alarm switch was hidden .
- Can I go ? - Can I ?
No , you 'll stay here too .
This is absurd . I 've provided an alibi .
- The Marquis confirmed it . - It 's true . We were together .
Don 't worry , gentlemen , I haven 't forgotten .
You were together until gone 11 . Nicole was killed after 10 .
- So why do you need us ? - Well ...
When I called Peggy to tell her that we 'd found her car ,
it was about half past 11 .
I got to her place a quarter of an hour later ,
but she was no longer there and the house was in a complete mess .
Maybe they killed her too and hid her body somewhere .
As far as this last event is concerned , gentlemen ,
I 'd say your alibi was pretty useless .
It 's already nine o 'clock .
Why do we have to sit in the dark ? As if we weren 't scared enough already .
Do what you want , but try to stay calm .
How can we stay calm ?
Aren 't you worried about everything that 's happened ?
I 'm scared too , I admit it .
But there 's no point in panicking .
I wish some of the men would come back .
We 're the only ones left at the studio .
Hello ?
Mr Morlachi , at last . What 's happened ?
What ?
That 's ridiculous . Why ? What right do they have ?
Oh , yes .
I see .
All right .
Of course .
Yes , don 't worry .
All right .
- They 've detained all five of them . - Why ?
Clearly the police believe that one of them is the murderer .
I knew it .
Madame ...
can we go ?
Yes , please go .
Be strong .
- Good night . - Good night .
I really envy those three living together .
At least they can keep each other company .
- I 'm going too , Madame . - Yes , of course .
Wait ... Why don 't you come and sleep at my house tonight ?
What ? I just live round the corner .
Why should I go all the way to yours out in the country ?
I could come and sleep at your house , then .
No , I 'm sorry , but I 'd rather be on my own .
And I think you 'd feel even more afraid at my house .
Aren 't you scared on your own ? They lived with you .
Isabella 's been killed , and Peggy ...
Yes , I know .
But I 'm certain that nothing will happen tonight .
All the men have been detained
and I 'm sure one of them is the murderer .
- Good night , Madame . - Good night .
Madame , I don 't want to go home , I want to sleep here .
No , my dear . You need to go like the others . Good night .
But I 'm frightened . I live out of town in a house on its own .
Don 't be a baby , Greta . We 've got a big day tomorrow .
Work must go on .
Listen ...
Isabella and Nicole were mixed up in a nasty business
that doesn 't concern us .
We 've got nothing to be frightened of . Do you understand ?
Off you go . Don 't worry .
- Good night , Madame . - Good night .
Good night .
Miss ...
Miss , the Marquis called to say
that something came up and he 's stuck in town .
I know . Can you make me some tea , please ?
Right away , miss .
Hello ? Hello ?
I 've brought your tea , miss .
Just a moment , please .
Come in .
Leave it up there , Charles . I can do it myself .
Good night , miss .
Did you see how the murderer attacked that poor girl ?
He must have used a red-hot iron . We 're dealing with a madman here .
Or a homicidal sex maniac .
- Who only kills beautiful girls . - Exactly .
Perhaps female beauty makes him lose his head and kill .
We 're going to have to start again from scratch .
Inspector , Forensics are outside if you want to see the footprints in the garden .
The footprints start over there .
The murderer drove up here on this road ,
got out and walked down the slope to the house .
The prints match the ones found in the studio gardens .
- Are you sure ? - Yes , we took casts of them .
I could have sworn the culprit was one of the five men we detained .
- We 'll have to release them at once . - Of course .
This time they really do have a cast-iron alibi .
And I provided them with it .
Riccardo Morelli . Make sure everything 's there .
Massimo Morlachi .
Come in .
Mr Morlachi , I 'd like to speak to you for a moment if I may .
Yes , dear . Come in .
Mr Morlachi , I 'm a calm woman , I 'm not at all nervous .
But I find the thought of a sex maniac prowling around our studio
really very disturbing .
I 've decided to take some holiday .
I 've booked a seat on the flight to Paris tomorrow .
Paris ?
- All right , Tao-Li . - Thank you .
By the way , are you still living in the countess 's house ?
- Yes . Why ? - Nothing . Just memories .
When the count was alive I 'd often go and visit them .
It 's a beautiful house .
I remember being able to see all over Rome from the terrace .
Yes , but right now I 'd rather see the rooftops of Paris .
- I don 't doubt that . Have fun . - Goodbye .
Search as much as you like . I burnt everything that could compromise you .
When I heard you 'd been arrested
I got rid of Peggy 's body .
They could have found it .
And I killed Greta to give you an alibi .
Perfect .
Perfect but horrible .
I don 't know how I did it .
I 'd never have thought I 'd have the strength to kill .
But I did it for you .
I can imagine what it cost you .
But tell me , how did you manage to take Peggy 's body to Morelli 's house ?
I didn 't take her there myself .
I just put her in the boot ...
and Greta did the rest .
Why did you decide to use Greta ?
Well , I knew she 'd be on her own at home .
- That made everything easier . - Well done .
The police are convinced they 're dealing with a sex maniac .
Isabella , Nicole ...
Peggy ...
and now , with Greta , that makes four .
Stop it .
Sweetheart , what 's wrong ?
Kiss me .
Are you worried , darling ?
What a mess .
It 's all because of that stupid idiot Isabella .
Her blackmail had become unbearable .
Money , money and more money .
Precisely because she unfortunately found out ...
that my husband 's death wasn 't an accident ,
she should have realised that it was both foolish and dangerous to push it .
But no ... No ...
The more we gave her , the more she wanted .
- She asked for it . - She thought she had us on a string .
She felt like she was the only witness to a perfect crime .
Her death would have been perfect too ,
if only that bloody diary hadn 't cropped up .
But it 's all over now .
We 've got nothing to worry about now , darling . Nothing at all .
No , that 's where you 're wrong . Very wrong .
The two of us will never have any peace
until we give the police a culprit .
Peace !
Listen to me .
We 'll never get away with it
unless we put a face to their sex maniac .
Until they catch him they 'll be watching us .
All the girls who were killed worked at the studio .
They 've got no proof against us but the case has become a sensation .
It 's all over the papers . The scandal 's raging .
We need to find a solution .
So what do you want to do ?
I know , darling . We should go away to the moon .
We need to kill one last time .
And you 'll be the one who does it .
- No . - Yes .
They 're definitely watching me .
Don 't worry , darling , I 'll create a perfect alibi for you .
Stay calm .
No , Massimo . You can 't ask me to do a thing like that .
I refuse . I can 't do it . Do you understand ?
You 've done it already .
Yes , you 're right , I 've done it already ,
but I had a very different motive then .
You were in danger . I had no choice .
I knew that if I didn 't do it
I 'd have lost you forever .
My love for you gave me the strength to do it .
But it was horrible .
Horrible !
Don 't cry . Listen to me .
You need to do what I say . You have to kill Tao-Li .
You have to make it look like suicide . Do you understand ?
They 'Il find the mask by her side
and think that she was the culprit .
If we don 't do it , everything we 've done so far will have been pointless .
You 're surprised to see me alive , aren 't you , Massimo ?
Your plan was certainly very ingenious .
It was going to be perfect , just the way you like it ,
but you didn 't reckon
on the shop awning
breaking my fall .
Please ...
Be quiet .
I know very well what you 'd like to say . You 'd like to deny it .
But I saw you with the jewels . You planned everything .
Only you knew that I 'd use the ledge if I was in danger .
Remember ? You were the one who suggested it . It was your idea .
Cristiana , I swear it was an accident .
Do you really still think that you can fool me ?
Yes ...
Yes , it was a very ingenious plan .
They 'd have found me dressed like this
and everything would have been clear
and you 'd have been free .
Now I understand why you wanted to marry me in secret
and in such a hurry .
You were so in love with me . So in love .
You were , but with my villa , the house ,
the studio , my money ...
You wanted to get your hands on everything I own by killing me .
Cristiana , I beg you ...
You 're wrong , darling . It 's not true .
It 's not true .
You 're imagining it all , darling . Believe me .
I swear , Cristiana ...
It was just an accident . I didn 't mean it to happen .
How could you think that ?
I love you , darling , so much .
We 'll go away . We 'll be together forever .
I 'll never leave you .
Police ...
Get me ...
Get me Inspector Silverstri ...